an Pereira

Front End Engineer

Jogeshwari, 400060, Mumbai, Maharashtra IN

y pereiraryan20 in Ryan Pereira 🗘 pereiraryan 🔊 pereiraryan 🗞 pereiraryan



A technology professional with over 5 years of experience in software engineering and web development, I have a bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering from the University of Mumbai. My objective is to ameliorate practical skills and gain first hand experience in building and designing products which can help solving problems. My Technology proficiencies include building user interfaces for websites and web applications.

SKILLS

Web Development

Master

html5 | css3 | javascript | typescript | jquery | react.js | wordpress | php | laravel

Project Management

Intermediate

sprint planing | requirements documenting | time management

Testing Intermediate

soap wsdl and rest api testing | unit testing | integration testing | functional testing

Web Analytics

Intermediate

webmaster tools | google tag manager | google analytics | ga datalayers | datadog rum integration

DevOps Intermediate

ci/cd processes | bamboo builds and deployments | docker | okd4

Version Control

Master

git

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Web Developer at Newfold Digital April 2017- Current

newfold.com

Newfold Digital is a leading web technology company serving nearly seven million customers globally. Established in 2021 through the combination of leading web services providers Endurance Web Presence and Web.com Group, it's portfolio of brands includes: Bluehost, BigRock, ResellerClub, CrazyDomains, HostGator, Network Solutions, Register.com, Web.com and many others.

- Responsible for innovating and managing new and existing properties across Newfold Digital.
- Maintain the front of site properties by managing their security, building marketing collaterals, coordination with stakeholders and routinely updating them for business-as-usual tasks.
- Creating innovative landing pages for both online & offline marketing campaigns.
- Bringing visual designs to life in standards compliant, clean markup.
- Complete front end tasks, including new features, current site updates and changes, and bug fixes.
- Building complete end-to-end workflows in git and automated integration tools for DevOps/Container Technologies: Jenkins, Git, Docker, Artifactory, Kubernetes

Software Engineer at Majesco June 2016- April 2017

majesco.com

Majesco Inc. (formerly MajescoMastek) is a multinational provider of insurance technology software, information technology services and consulting to insurance carriers worldwide across lines of business - property & casualty (general insurance), life, annuity, health, pensions, and group & worksite benefits insurance

- Worked as an ICD/ICM developer
- Developed YAWL flows, defining and updating Object Models and Mappings on the Proprietary Toolkit for the insurance business
- Worked with developers to ensure new environments both meet their requirements and configurations to industrystandard best practices.
- Responsible for deployment of web application on JBoss servers
- Developed UI application "Batch Automation Testing" using angular.js for the testing team to run their scenarios.
- Carry out Unit testing on system applications using SOAP and WSDL based services.

VOLUNTEER

Quality Assurance at do_action India

August 2020 - August 2020

https://doaction.org/event/india-2020/

do_action is a charity hackathon that uses WordPress to uplift local communities

Volunteered as a Quality Assurance Tester for the project sangcollective.org.

Volunteer at WordCamp Mumbai

March 2017 - February 2021

https://2018.mumbai.wordcamp.org

WordCamp is a conference that focuses on everything WordPress. WordCamps are informal, community-organized events that are put together by WordPress users

Helped in organizing the Speakers event.

Attendee at ProductFoo

March 2019 - March 2019

https://www.productfoo.com

ProductFoo is an open-space unconference run by Product Managers for Product Managers.

Spoke on change management and requirement gathering.

Participant at Ethereal Virtual Hackathon

April 2019 - April 2019

https://gitcoin.co/hackathon/ethhack2019

The largest Ethereum virtual hackathon.

 Built the frontend for Robin Hood-like dApp where millenials and Gen Zs invest in digital land and property from Decentraland.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering Computer Science at University of Mumbai **2012 - 2016**

Major courses: computer science

Grade: 6.95 CGPI

AWARDS

The Einstein Award for Delivering Perfection at Endurance Awards **2018**

Ryan has displayed exemplary performance and played a key role in making sure all of our Web portals are GDPR & PCI compliant, in accordance to the rules laid down by our internal Privacy teams. His proactive activities and coordination with several teams internally has made sure he delivered perfection in every aspect of this project, thereby making sure other teams look at our activities and follow suit as well as helping the brand be compliant in all means.